<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Bruno F. Lourenço</title>
    <link>/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Bruno F. Lourenço</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Amenable cones are particularly nice&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2020/11/17/preprint-amenable-cones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/11/17/preprint-amenable-cones/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv and OO
Authors Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM), Vera Roshchina (UNSW), James Saunderson (Monash U.)
Abstract Amenability is a geometric property of convex cones that is stronger than facial exposedness and assists in the study of error bounds for conic feasibility problems. In this paper we establish numerous properties of amenable cones, and investigate the relationships between amenability and other properties of convex cones, such as niceness and projectional exposure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Solving SDP Completely with an Interior Point Oracle&#34; was accepted at the Optimization Methods and Software journal</title>
      <link>/news/2020/11/11/accepted-solving-completely/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/11/11/accepted-solving-completely/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Masakazu Muramatsu (UEC), Takashi Tsuchiya (GRIPS) &amp;ldquo;Solving SDP Completely with an Interior Point Oracle&amp;rdquo; was accepted at the Optimization Methods and Software journal. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Error bounds, facial residual functions and applications to the exponential cone&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2020/10/30/preprint-facial-residual-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/10/30/preprint-facial-residual-functions/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv and and OO
Authors Scott B. Lindstrom (Hong Kong Poly. U.), Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM), Ting Kei Pong (Hong Kong Poly. U.)
Abstract We construct a general framework for deriving error bounds for conic feasibility problems. In particular, our approach allows one to work with cones that fail to be amenable or even to have computable projections, two previously challenging barriers. For the purpose, we first show how error bounds may be constructed using objects called facial residual functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Generalized subdifferentials of spectral functions over Euclidean Jordan algebras&#34; was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Optimization</title>
      <link>/news/2020/10/19/accepted-spectral-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/10/19/accepted-spectral-functions/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Akiko Takeda (U.Tokyo) &amp;ldquo;Generalized subdifferentials of spectral functions over Euclidean Jordan algebras&amp;rdquo; was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Optimization. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Convergence analysis under consistent error bounds&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2020/08/29/preprint-convergence-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/08/29/preprint-convergence-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Available at OO and arxiv
Authors Tianxiang Liu (RIKEN-AIP) and Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM)
Abstract We introduce the notion of consistent error bound functions which provides a unifying framework for error bounds for multiple convex sets. This framework goes beyond the classical Lipschitzian and Hölderian error bounds and includes, for example, the error bounds obtainable under the theory of amenable cones. One of the main results we prove is that the convergence rate of several algorithms for feasibility problems can be expressed explicitly in terms of the underlying consistent error bound function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;A simplified treatment of Ramana&#39;s exact dual for semidefinite programming&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2020/06/17/preprint-ramana-dual/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/06/17/preprint-ramana-dual/</guid>
      <description>Available at OO
Authors Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM) and Gábor Pataki (UNC-Chapel Hill)
Abstract In semidefinite programming the dual may fail to attain its optimal value and there could be a duality gap, i.e., the primal and dual optimal values may differ. In a striking paper, Ramana proposed a polynomial size extended dual that does not have these deficiencies and yields a number of fundamental results in complexity theory. The known expositions of Ramana&amp;rsquo;s dual tend to be somewhat technical; here we give a concise and self-contained derivation, relying mostly on elementary linear algebra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Random projection of Linear and Semidefinite problem with linear inequalities&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2020/06/01/preprint-random-projection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/06/01/preprint-random-projection/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv
Authors Pierre-Louis Poirion (RIKEN-AIP), Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM) and Akiko Takeda (University of Tokyo)
Abstract The Johnson-Lindenstrauss Lemma states that there exist linear maps that project a set of points of a vector space into a space of much lower dimension such that the Euclidean distance between these points is approximately preserved. This lemma has been previously used to prove that we can randomly aggregate, using a random matrix whose entries are drawn from a zero-mean sub-Gaussian distribution, the equality constraints of an Linear Program (LP) while preserving approximately the value of the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moved to the Institute of Statistical Mathematics</title>
      <link>/news/2020/04/01/moved-to-ism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/04/01/moved-to-ism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>