<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Bruno F. Lourenço</title>
    <link>/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Bruno F. Lourenço</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Closing duality gaps of SDPs completely through perturbation when singularity degree is one&#34; was accepted at  Optimization Methods and Software.</title>
      <link>/news/2024/09/24/accepted-perturb-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/09/24/accepted-perturb-gap/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with T. Tsuchiya (GRIPS), M. Muramatsu (UEC) and T. Okuno (Seikei University) was accepted at Optimization Methods and Software. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Concrete convergence rates for common fixed point problems under Karamata regularity&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2024/07/19/fix_karamata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/07/19/fix_karamata/</guid>
      <description>Available at OO, arxiv.
Authors Tianxiang Liu (Tokyo Institute of Technology); Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM).
Abstract We introduce the notion of Karamata regular operators, which is a notion of regularity that is suitable for obtaining concrete convergence rates for common fixed point problems. This provides a broad framework that includes, but goes beyond, Hölderian error bounds and Hölder regular operators. By concrete, we mean that the rates we obtain are explicitly expressed in terms of a function of the iteration number \({k}\) instead, of say, a function of the iterate \({x^k}\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Projection onto hyperbolicity cones and beyond: a dual Frank-Wolfe approach&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2024/06/23/hyper_proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/06/23/hyper_proj/</guid>
      <description>Available at OO.
Authors Takayuki Nagano (U. Tokyo); Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM); Akiko Takeda (U. Tokyo).
Abstract We discuss the problem of projecting a point onto an arbitrary hyperbolicity cone from both theoretical and numerical perspectives. While hyperbolicity cones are furnished with a generalization of the notion of eigenvalues, obtaining closed form expressions for the projection operator as in the case of semidefinite matrices is an elusive endeavour. To address that we propose a Frank-Wolfe method to handle this task and, more generally, strongly convex optimization over closed convex cones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Eigenvalue programming beyond matrices&#34; was accepted at Computational Optimization and Applications.</title>
      <link>/news/2024/06/15/accepted-eig-opt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/06/15/accepted-eig-opt/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Masaru Ito (Nihon U.) was accepted at Computational Optimization and Applications. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Minimal hyperbolic polynomials and ranks of homogeneous cones&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2024/04/05/preprint-min-hyp-rank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/04/05/preprint-min-hyp-rank/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv.
Authors Masaru Ito (Nihon U.); João Gouveia (University of Coimbra); Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM).
Abstract The starting point of this paper is the computation of minimal hyperbolic polynomials of duals of cones arising from chordal sparsity patterns. From that, we investigate the relation between ranks of homogeneous cones and their minimal polynomials. Along the way, we answer in the negative a question posed in an earlier paper and show examples of homogeneous cones that cannot be realized as rank-one generated (ROG) hyperbolicity cones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Optimal error bounds in the absence of constraint qualifications with applications to the p-cones and beyond&#34; was accepted at Mathematics of Operations Research</title>
      <link>/news/2024/03/26/accepted-p-cone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/03/26/accepted-p-cone/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Scott B. Lindstrom (Curtin U.) and Ting Kei Pong (Hong Kong Poly. U.) was accepted at Mathematics of Operations Research. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Tight error bounds for log-determinant cones without constraint qualifications&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2024/03/13/preprint-logdet-err/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/03/13/preprint-logdet-err/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv.
Authors Ying Lin (Hong Kong Poly. U.), Scott B. Lindstrom (Curtin U.), Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM), Ting Kei Pong (Hong Kong Poly. U.)
Abstract In this paper, without requiring any constraint qualifications, we establish tight error bounds for the log-determinant cone, which is the closure of the hypograph of the perspective function of the log-determinant function. This error bound is obtained using the recently developed framework based on one-step facial residual functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Non-facial exposedness of copositive cones over symmetric cones&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2024/02/20/preprint-cop-sym/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024/02/20/preprint-cop-sym/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv.
Authors Mitsuhiro Nishijima (Tokyo Tech) and B. F. Lourenço (ISM)
Abstract In this paper, we consider copositive cones over symmetric cones and show that they are never facially exposed when the underlying cone has dimension at least 2. We do so by explicitly exhibiting a non-exposed extreme ray. Our result extends the known fact that the cone of copositive matrices over the nonnegative orthant is not facially exposed in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Generalized power cones: optimal error bounds and automorphisms&#34; was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Optimization.</title>
      <link>/news/2023/12/20/accepted-power-cone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/12/20/accepted-power-cone/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Ying Lin (Hong Kong Poly. U.), Scott B. Lindstrom (Curtin U.) and Ting Kei Pong (Hong Kong Poly. U.) was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Optimization. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Eigenvalue programming beyond matrices&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2023/09/28/preprint-dual-gap_perturb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/09/28/preprint-dual-gap_perturb/</guid>
      <description>Available at OO.
Authors Masaru Ito (Nihon U.) and B. F. Lourenço (ISM)
Abstract In this paper we analyze and solve eigenvalue programs, which consist of the task of minimizing a function subject to constraints on the &amp;ldquo;eigenvalues&amp;rdquo; of the decision variable. Here, by making use of the FTvN systems framework introduced by Gowda, we interpret &amp;ldquo;eigenvalues&amp;rdquo; in a broad fashion going beyond the usual eigenvalues of matrices. This allows us to shed new light on classical problems such as inverse eigenvalues problems and also leads to new applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Closing Duality Gaps of SDPs through Perturbation&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2023/04/10/preprint-dual-gap_perturb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/04/10/preprint-dual-gap_perturb/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv.
Authors T. Tsuchiya (GRIPS), B. F. Lourenço (ISM), M. Muramatsu (UEC) and T. Okuno (Seikei University)
Abstract Let \(({\bf P},{\bf D})\) be a primal-dual pair of SDPs with a nonzero finite duality gap. Under such circumstances, \({\bf P}\) and \({\bf D}\) are weakly feasible and if we perturb the problem data to recover strong feasibility, the (common) optimal value function \(v\) as a function of the perturbation is not well-defined at zero (unperturbed data) since there are &amp;ldquo;two different optimal values&amp;rdquo; \(v({\bf P})\) and \(v({\bf D})\), where \(v({\bf P})\) and \(v({\bf D})\) are the optimal values of \({\bf P}\) and \({\bf D}\) respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Hyperbolicity cones are amenable&#34; was accepted at the Mathematical Programming journal.</title>
      <link>/news/2023/03/20/accepted-hyper-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/03/20/accepted-hyper-am/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Vera Roshchina (UNSW) and James Saunderson (Monash U.) was accepted at the Mathematical Programming journal. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Self-dual polyhedral cones and their slack matrices&#34; was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Matrix Analysis.</title>
      <link>/news/2023/02/28/accepted-slack-poly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/02/28/accepted-slack-poly/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with João Gouveia (University of Coimbra) Self-dual polyhedral cones and their slack matrices&amp;rdquo; was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Matrix Analysis. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Automorphisms of rank-one generated hyperbolicity cones and their derivative relaxations&#34; was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Applied Algebra and Geometry</title>
      <link>/news/2023/01/27/accepted-hyper-aut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/01/27/accepted-hyper-aut/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Masaru Ito (Nihon University) &amp;ldquo;Automorphisms of rank-one generated hyperbolicity cones and their derivative relaxations&amp;rdquo;, was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Applied Algebra and Geometry. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Random projections of linear and semidefinite problems with linear inequalities&#34; was accepted at Linear Algebra and its Applications</title>
      <link>/news/2023/01/17/accepted-rand-proj-cone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2023/01/17/accepted-rand-proj-cone/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Pierre-Louis Poirion (RIKEN-AIP) and Akiko Takeda (U. Tokyo) &amp;ldquo;Random projection of Linear and Semidefinite problem with linear inequalities&amp;rdquo;, was accepted at Linear Algebra and its Applications. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Optimal error bounds in the absence of constraint qualifications for the generalized power cones, and further applications&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2022/11/29/preprint-power-cones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/11/29/preprint-power-cones/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv.
Authors Ying Lin (Hong Kong Poly. U.), Scott B. Lindstrom (Curtin U.), Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM), Ting Kei Pong (Hong Kong Poly. U.)
Abstract Error bounds are a requisite for trusting or distrusting solutions in an informed way. Until recently, provable error bounds in the absence of constraint qualifications were unattainable for many classes of cones that do not admit projections with known succinct expressions. We build such error bounds for the generalized power cones, using the recently developed framework of one-step facial residual functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;A Limiting Analysis on Regularization of Singular SDP and its Implication to Infeasible Interior-point Algorithms&#34; was accepted at  Mathematical Programming</title>
      <link>/news/2022/09/05/accepted-iipm-ssdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/09/05/accepted-iipm-ssdp/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with T. Tsuchiya (GRIPS), M. Muramatsu (UEC) and T. Okuno (Seikei University) &amp;ldquo;A Limiting Analysis on Regularization of Singular SDP and its Implication to Infeasible Interior-point Algorithms&amp;rdquo;, was accepted at the Mathematical Programming journal. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Error bounds, facial residual functions and applications to the exponential cone&#34; was accepted at  Mathematical Programming</title>
      <link>/news/2022/08/14/accepted-exp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/08/14/accepted-exp/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Scott B. Lindstrom (Curtin University) and Ting Kei Pong (Hong Kong Polytechnic University) &amp;ldquo;Error bounds, facial residual functions and applications to the exponential cone&amp;rdquo;, was accepted at the Mathematical Programming journal. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Self-dual polyhedral cones and their slack matrices&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2022/07/26/preprint-slack-self-dual/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/07/26/preprint-slack-self-dual/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv.
Authors João Gouveia (University of Coimbra), Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM)
Abstract We analyze self-dual polyhedral cones and prove several properties about their slack matrices. In particular, we show that self-duality is equivalent to the existence of a positive semidefinite (PSD) slack. Beyond that, we show that if the underlying cone is irreducible, then the corresponding PSD slacks are not only doubly nonnegative matrices (DNN) but are extreme rays of the DNN matrices, which correspond to a family of extreme rays not previously described.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Automorphisms of rank-one generated hyperbolicity cones and their derivative relaxations&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2022/07/25/preprint-hyper-aut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/07/25/preprint-hyper-aut/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv.
Authors Masaru Ito (Nihon University), Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM)
Abstract A hyperbolicity cone is said to be rank-one generated (ROG) if all its extreme rays have rank one, where the rank is computed with respect the underlying hyperbolic polynomial. This is a natural class of hyperbolicity cones which are strictly more general than the ROG spectrahedral cones. In this work, we present a study of the automorphisms of ROG hyperbolicity cones and their derivative relaxations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Convergence analysis under consistent error bounds&#34; was accepted at Foundations of Computational Mathematics</title>
      <link>/news/2022/06/14/accepted-consistent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/06/14/accepted-consistent/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Tianxiang Liu (Tokyo Tech) &amp;ldquo;Convergence analysis under consistent error bounds&amp;rdquo;, was accepted at Foundations of Computational Mathematics. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;A simplified treatment of Ramana&#39;s exact dual for semidefinite programming&#34; was accepted at Optimization Letters</title>
      <link>/news/2022/05/20/accepted-ramana-dual/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/05/20/accepted-ramana-dual/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Gábor Pataki (UNC at Chapel Hill) &amp;ldquo;A simplified treatment of Ramana&amp;rsquo;s exact dual for semidefinite programming&amp;rdquo;, was accepted at Optimization Letters. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Amenable cones are particularly nice&#34; was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Optimization</title>
      <link>/news/2022/04/17/accepted-amenable-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/04/17/accepted-amenable-nice/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Vera Roshchina (UNSW) and James Saunderson (Monash University) &amp;ldquo;Amenable cones are particularly nice&amp;rdquo;, was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Optimization. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation at OWOS</title>
      <link>/news/2022/03/17/presentation-owos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022/03/17/presentation-owos/</guid>
      <description>See video here and slides here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Optimal error bounds in the absence of constraint qualifications with applications to the p-cones and beyond&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2021/09/27/preprint-p-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021/09/27/preprint-p-error/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv and OO
Authors Scott B. Lindstrom (Curtin U.), Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM), Ting Kei Pong (Hong Kong Poly. U.)
Abstract We prove tight Hölderian error bounds for all p-cones. Surprisingly, the exponents differ in several ways from those that have been previously conjectured; moreover, they illuminate p-cones as a curious example of a class of objects that possess properties in 3 dimensions that they do not in 4 or more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Hyperbolicity cones are amenable&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2021/02/15/preprint-hyper-amenable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021/02/15/preprint-hyper-amenable/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv
Authors Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM), Vera Roshchina (UNSW), James Saunderson (Monash U.)
Abstract Amenability is a notion of facial exposedness for convex cones that is stronger than being facially dual complete (or &amp;lsquo;nice&amp;rsquo;) which is, in turn, stronger than merely being facially exposed. Hyperbolicity cones are a family of algebraically structured closed convex cones that contain all spectrahedra (linear sections of positive semidefinite cones) as special cases. It is known that all spectrahedra are amenable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Amenable cones are particularly nice&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2020/11/17/preprint-amenable-cones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/11/17/preprint-amenable-cones/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv and OO
Authors Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM), Vera Roshchina (UNSW), James Saunderson (Monash U.)
Abstract Amenability is a geometric property of convex cones that is stronger than facial exposedness and assists in the study of error bounds for conic feasibility problems. In this paper we establish numerous properties of amenable cones, and investigate the relationships between amenability and other properties of convex cones, such as niceness and projectional exposure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Solving SDP Completely with an Interior Point Oracle&#34; was accepted at the Optimization Methods and Software journal</title>
      <link>/news/2020/11/11/accepted-solving-completely/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/11/11/accepted-solving-completely/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Masakazu Muramatsu (UEC), Takashi Tsuchiya (GRIPS) &amp;ldquo;Solving SDP Completely with an Interior Point Oracle&amp;rdquo; was accepted at the Optimization Methods and Software journal. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Error bounds, facial residual functions and applications to the exponential cone&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2020/10/30/preprint-facial-residual-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/10/30/preprint-facial-residual-functions/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv and and OO
Authors Scott B. Lindstrom (Hong Kong Poly. U.), Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM), Ting Kei Pong (Hong Kong Poly. U.)
Abstract We construct a general framework for deriving error bounds for conic feasibility problems. In particular, our approach allows one to work with cones that fail to be amenable or even to have computable projections, two previously challenging barriers. For the purpose, we first show how error bounds may be constructed using objects called facial residual functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper &#34;Generalized subdifferentials of spectral functions over Euclidean Jordan algebras&#34; was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Optimization</title>
      <link>/news/2020/10/19/accepted-spectral-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/10/19/accepted-spectral-functions/</guid>
      <description>Our paper co-authored with Akiko Takeda (U.Tokyo) &amp;ldquo;Generalized subdifferentials of spectral functions over Euclidean Jordan algebras&amp;rdquo; was accepted at the SIAM Journal on Optimization. [arxiv link]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Convergence analysis under consistent error bounds&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2020/08/29/preprint-convergence-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/08/29/preprint-convergence-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Available at OO and arxiv
Authors Tianxiang Liu (RIKEN-AIP) and Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM)
Abstract We introduce the notion of consistent error bound functions which provides a unifying framework for error bounds for multiple convex sets. This framework goes beyond the classical Lipschitzian and Hölderian error bounds and includes, for example, the error bounds obtainable under the theory of amenable cones. One of the main results we prove is that the convergence rate of several algorithms for feasibility problems can be expressed explicitly in terms of the underlying consistent error bound function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;A simplified treatment of Ramana&#39;s exact dual for semidefinite programming&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2020/06/17/preprint-ramana-dual/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/06/17/preprint-ramana-dual/</guid>
      <description>Available at OO
Authors Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM) and Gábor Pataki (UNC-Chapel Hill)
Abstract In semidefinite programming the dual may fail to attain its optimal value and there could be a duality gap, i.e., the primal and dual optimal values may differ. In a striking paper, Ramana proposed a polynomial size extended dual that does not have these deficiencies and yields a number of fundamental results in complexity theory. The known expositions of Ramana&amp;rsquo;s dual tend to be somewhat technical; here we give a concise and self-contained derivation, relying mostly on elementary linear algebra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint &#34;Random projection of Linear and Semidefinite problem with linear inequalities&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/2020/06/01/preprint-random-projection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/06/01/preprint-random-projection/</guid>
      <description>Available at arxiv
Authors Pierre-Louis Poirion (RIKEN-AIP), Bruno F. Lourenço (ISM) and Akiko Takeda (University of Tokyo)
Abstract The Johnson-Lindenstrauss Lemma states that there exist linear maps that project a set of points of a vector space into a space of much lower dimension such that the Euclidean distance between these points is approximately preserved. This lemma has been previously used to prove that we can randomly aggregate, using a random matrix whose entries are drawn from a zero-mean sub-Gaussian distribution, the equality constraints of an Linear Program (LP) while preserving approximately the value of the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moved to the Institute of Statistical Mathematics</title>
      <link>/news/2020/04/01/moved-to-ism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020/04/01/moved-to-ism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>